Guide to the Robert Henri Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1878-1958; Series I; 7.9; (19 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Henri, Robert
      - The Fellowship of the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1902-15 (Box 4, Folder 84)
        See also: The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, box 7, folder 184
      - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor, 1924 Dec 7 (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Fleming, Roy F., 1913 (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Florance, Mary E. and Eustace [?] L., 1895-1900 (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Frost, Arthur B., Jr., 1906 (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - "G" general, 1904-26 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Giles, Howard, [1921]-27 (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - Glackens, William J. and Edith
        - Correspondence, [1897]-1914 (Box 4, Folder 91)
        - Correspondence, 1916-[29] (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Golz, Julius, 1917-19 (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - Grafly, Charles, 1883-1919, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - Grand Rapids Art Association, 1915-16 (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - Gregg, Frederick James, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - "H" general, 1888-1926, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 97-98)
      - Haefeker, W. A., 1889-92 (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - Hambidge, Mary Crovatt, 1924 May 21 (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - Hare, Elizabeth and Kate R., 1926-27 (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - Harris, Hartman Kuhn
        - Correspondence, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 102)
        - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 103-104)
        - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 105)
        - Correspondence, 1909, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 106)
      - Harrison, Birge
        - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 107)
        - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 108)
        - Correspondence, 1916-18 (Box 5, Folder 109)
      - Harrison, William Preston
        - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 110)
        - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 111)
        - Correspondence, 1925-27 (Box 5, Folder 112)
      - Hartmann, Sadakichi, 1925 Mar 5 (Box 5, Folder 113)
      - Hawthorne, Charles Webster, 1905 Jan 1 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      - Hewett, Edgar L., 1921 (Box 5, Folder 115)
      - Irons & Sweeney, 1916 Nov 10 (Box 5, Folder 116)
      - Isaac Delgado Museum of Art, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 117)
      - "J" general, 1907-25 (Box 5, Folder 118)
      - Jamieson, Alexander, [1897?], 1899 (Box 5, Folder 119)
      - J.B. Lippincott Company
        See also: Ryerson, Margery, box 9, folders 218-219
        - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 120)
        - Correspondence, 1923 Apr (Box 5, Folder 121)
        - Correspondence, 1923 May (Box 5, Folder 122)
        - Correspondence, 1923 Jun-Dec (Box 5, Folder 123)
        - Correspondence, 1924-38 (Box 5, Folder 124)
      - Johnson, W. J., 1913-[16] (Box 5, Folder 125)
      - Johnston, Virginia del C., 1909-22 (Box 5, Folder 126)
      - "K" general, 1892-1924 (Box 5, Folder 127)
      - Kahn, Otto, 1926 Mar 29 (Box 5, Folder 128)
      - The Kansas City Art Institute, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 129)
      - Kelly, James P., 1892 Jul 24 (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Kent, Rockwell, 1905-28 (Box 5, Folder 131)
      - Komroff, Manuel, 1915-29 (Box 5, Folder 132)
      - Koopman, Augustus, 1888 May 7 (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - Kroll, Leon, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 134)
      - Kuhn, Walt, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 135)
      - "L" general, 1888-1927 (Box 5, Folder 136-137)
      - La Farge, John, 1906 Jun 11 (Box 6, Folder 138)
      - Lahey, Richard, 1921 Dec 10 (Box 6, Folder 139)
      - Lathrop, Elise, 1906, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 140)
      - Law, Margaret M., 1924 (Box 6, Folder 141)
      - Lawson, Ernest, 1906-[14?], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Lindsay, Vachel, 1905-25 (Box 6, Folder 143)
      - Londoner, Amy, [1921?]-28 (Box 6, Folder 144)
      - Lovins, Henry, 1908-17 (Box 6, Folder 145)
      - Luks, George Benjamin, [1901?-02?], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 146)
      - Luxembourg Exhibition
        - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 147)
        - Correspondence, 1920, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 148)
      - "M" general, 1897-1933 (Box 6, Folder 149-150)
      - McCarter, Henry, [1900?] (Box 6, Folder 151)
      - McCutcheon, George Barr, 1913-15 (Box 6, Folder 152)
      - Maratta, Hardesty Gilmore, 1918-19 (Box 6, Folder 153)
      - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1921, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 154)
      - Melchers, Gari, 1919-27 (Box 6, Folder 155)
      - Montclair Art Association, 1915-26 (Box 6, Folder 156)
      - Morrice, James W., [1896?-1906?] (Box 6, Folder 157)
      - Morris, Harrison S., 1904-22 (Box 6, Folder 158)
      - Museum of New Mexico
        See: Hewett, Edgar L., box 5, folder 115
      - "N" general, 1902-28 (Box 6, Folder 159)
      - National Academy of Design, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 160)
        See also: Morris, Harrison S., box 6, folder 158
      - The National Arts Club, New York, N.Y., 1919-22 (Box 6, Folder 161)
      - New York (N.Y.) Department of Parks, 1915, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 162)
      - The New York School of Art, 1897-1908 (Box 6, Folder 163)
      - New York Tribune, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 164)
      - Niles, Helen
        - Correspondence, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 165)
        - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 166)
        - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 167)
        - Correspondence, 1911-13 (Box 7, Folder 168)
        - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 169)
        - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 170-171)
        - Correspondence, 1916-17 (Box 7, Folder 172)
        - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 173)
        - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 174)
        - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 175)
        - Correspondence, 1921-27, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 176)
      - Noyes, Carleton
        - Correspondence, [1901?]-02 (Box 7, Folder 177)
        - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 178)
        - Correspondence, 1904-05, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 179)
      - "O" general, 1921-24 (Box 7, Folder 180)
      - O'Donnell, Mary, 1930 Jan 8 (Box 7, Folder 181)
      - "P" general, 1907-24, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 182)
      - Pach, Walter, 1906, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 183)
        Includes: "Spanish Masters" article translated by Pach
      - The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1893, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 184)
        See also: The Fellowship of The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, box 4, folder 84
      - Potts, W. Sherman, 1919-21 (Box 7, Folder 185)
      - Prendergast, Maurice Brazil, 1919 Feb 19
        See: Luxembourg Exhibition, box 6, folders 147-148; and Prendergast to John Sloan in Others to Others, box 11, folder 281
      - Quinn, Edmond, 1925 Apr 7 (Box 7, Folder 186)
      - Randolph-Macon Woman's College, 1917-27 (Box 7, Folder 187)
      - Ravlin, G., 1918-[27?], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 188)
      - Raymond, Kathryn T., 1902-[07?] (Box 7, Folder 189)
      - Redfield, Edward W.
        - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 190)
        - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 191)
        - Correspondence, 1891-93 (Box 8, Folder 192)
        - Correspondence, 1894-96 (Box 8, Folder 193)
        - Correspondence, 1897-99 (Box 8, Folder 194)
        - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 195)
        - Correspondence, 1901 Jan-Apr (Box 8, Folder 196)
        - Correspondence, 1901 Nov-Dec (Box 8, Folder 197)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Jan-Mar (Box 8, Folder 198)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Apr-Dec (Box 8, Folder 199)
        - Correspondence, 1903 Feb-Apr (Box 8, Folder 200)
        - Correspondence, 1903 May-Jun (Box 8, Folder 201)
        - Correspondence, 1903 Jul-Dec (Box 8, Folder 202)
        - Correspondence, 1904 Jan-Feb (Box 8, Folder 203)
        - Correspondence, 1904 Mar-Oct (Box 8, Folder 204)
        - Correspondence, 1905-06 (Box 8, Folder 205)
        - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 206-208)
      - Rhodes, June Hamilton
        See: St. Denis, Ruth, box 9, folder 229
      - Robbins, [Leona?], [1913?], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 209)
      - Roberts, Mary Fanton and William Carman
        See also: Letters to the Roberts, in Third Party Correspondence, box 11, folder 282
        - Correspondence, 1908-17 (Box 9, Folder 210)
        - Correspondence, 1918-19 (Box 9, Folder 211)
        - Correspondence, 1923-24 (Box 9, Folder 212)
        - Correspondence, 1925-26 (Box 9, Folder 213)
        - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 214)
      - Rochfort, Constance, 1897-98 (Box 9, Folder 215)
      - Rudy, J. Horace, 1921 Feb 7 (Box 9, Folder 216)
      - Russell, Morgan, 1925-26 (Box 9, Folder 217)
      - Ryerson, Margery
        - Correspondence, 1922-23 (Box 9, Folder 218)
        - Correspondence, 1924-26 (Box 9, Folder 219)
      - "S" general, 1907-[28] (Box 9, Folder 220-222)
      - Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee, ca. 1921-27 (Box 9, Folder 223)
      - St. Denis, Ruth, 1927-28, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 224)
        Includes letters from June Hamilton Rhodes of Denishawn
      - Schofield, W. E., [1915-16], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 225)
      - Scott, [William Binden?], 1928 (Box 9, Folder 226)
      - Seton, Ernest Thompson
        - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 9, Folder 227)
        - Correspondence, 1892-94 (Box 9, Folder 228)
        - Correspondence, 1895-[1922] (Box 9, Folder 229)
      - Seyffert, Helen, 1920, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 230)
      - Sheeler, Charles, [1913?]-19, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 231)
      - Sheridan, Helen and Kiddo, [1924?], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 232)
      - Shinn, Everett, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 233)
      - Shore, Henrietta M., 1917-25 (Box 9, Folder 234)
      - Shuster, Will, 1923-26 (Box 9, Folder 235)
      - Skipper, Alice J., 1922 (Box 9, Folder 236)
      - Sloan, John
        - Correspondence, 1893-97 (Box 9, Folder 237)
        - Correspondence, 1898-99 (Box 10, Folder 238)
        - Correspondence, 1900-17 (Box 10, Folder 239)
          Includes two sketches by John Sloan
        - Correspondence, 1919-23 (Box 10, Folder 240)
        - Correspondence, 1926-28, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 241)
          Includes untitled poem by John Sloan
      - Smith, Edward H., 1918-19 (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - Society of American Arts and Letters Inc., 1927 (Box 10, Folder 243)
      - Spaulding, John Taylor, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 244)
      - Speicher, Eugene
        - Correspondence, [1923?]-26 (Box 10, Folder 245)
        - Correspondence, 1927-29 (Box 10, Folder 246)
      - Sprinchorn, Carl, 1919, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 247)
      - Springfield Art Association, [1918?]-19 (Box 10, Folder 248)
      - Stephenson, Byron, 1907 May 25 (Box 10, Folder 249)
      - Sterner, Marie, 1919-[24] (Box 10, Folder 250)
      - "T" general, 1889-1926 (Box 10, Folder 251)
      - The Taos Society of Artists, 1919-29 (Box 10, Folder 252)
      - The Toledo Museum of Art, 1917-19 (Box 10, Folder 253)
      - Traubel, Horace G. and Anne Montgomerie, 1913, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 254)
      - Van Slyck, Lucile W., [1928] Mar 8 (Box 10, Folder 255)
      - Vetter, Cornelia C., 1925 (Box 10, Folder 256)
      - "W" general, 1914-27 (Box 10, Folder 257)
      - Whittier, Robert, 1919, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 258)
      - Williamson, A. C.
        - Correspondence, 1898-[04?] (Box 10, Folder 259)
        - Correspondence, [1905?] (Box 10, Folder 260)
        - Correspondence, [1906?]-08, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 261)
      - Yeats, John Butler, 1919-21 (Box 10, Folder 262)
        Includes drawing by Yeats
      - Zug, George Breed, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 263)
      - Zuloaga, Ignacio, [before 1923] (Box 10, Folder 264)
      - Unidentified recipients, [1890s?-1918], n.d. (Box 10, Folder 265-268)
        May include letters to family
    - Organ, Violet
      - Church of the Epiphany, Germantown, 1958 May 2 (Box 11, Folder 269)
      - McPherson, John C., 1913 (Box 11, Folder 270)
        See also: Oversize, box 32, folder 703
      - Niles, Helen, 1939 May 29 (Box 11, Folder 271)
      - Roberts, Mary Fanton and William Carman, 1930 Jul 5 (Box 11, Folder 272)
      - Russell, Morgan, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 273)
      - Seton Thompson, Grace, 1952 May 5 (Box 11, Folder 274)
      - Sloan, John and Dolly, 1939, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 275)
      - Y., A., 1905 Aug 16 (Box 11, Folder 276)
      - Yeats, Jack B., 1925 Sep 25 (Box 11, Folder 277)
      - Unidentified, 1915-49, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 278)
    - Third Party Correspondence
      - Carpenter, H. T. to Editor of the New York American, 1907 Nov 23 (Box 11, Folder 279)
      - Jozkifspfowk [?], P. to Editor of the Evening Sun, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 280)
      - Maurice Prendergast to John Sloan, 1911 Dec 20 (Box 11, Folder 281)
      - Letters to Mary Fanton and William Carman Roberts, [1910?-22], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 282)
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Henri, Robert
      - Lee, Theresa Gatewood and Richard H.
        - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 11, Folder 283)
        - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 11, Folder 284)
        - Correspondence, 1888 Jan-Apr (Box 11, Folder 285)
        - Correspondence, 1888 Sep (Box 11, Folder 286)
        - Correspondence, 1888 Oct (Box 11, Folder 287)
        - Correspondence, 1888 Nov (Box 11, Folder 288)
        - Correspondence, 1888 Dec (Box 11, Folder 289)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Jan (Box 11, Folder 290-291)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Feb (Box 11, Folder 292)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Mar (Box 11, Folder 293-294)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Apr-May (Box 11, Folder 295)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Jun (Box 11, Folder 296)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Aug (Box 11, Folder 297)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Sep (Box 11, Folder 298)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Oct (Box 11, Folder 299)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Nov (Box 12, Folder 300-301)
        - Correspondence, 1889 Dec (Box 12, Folder 302-303)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Jan (Box 12, Folder 304-305)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Feb (Box 12, Folder 306-307)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Mar (Box 12, Folder 308)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Apr (Box 12, Folder 309-310)
        - Correspondence, 1890 May (Box 12, Folder 311-312)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Jun (Box 12, Folder 313)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Jul (Box 12, Folder 314)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Aug (Box 12, Folder 315)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Sep (Box 12, Folder 316-317)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Oct (Box 13, Folder 318-319)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Nov (Box 13, Folder 320)
        - Correspondence, 1890 Dec (Box 13, Folder 321-322)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Jan (Box 13, Folder 323-326)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Feb (Box 13, Folder 327-330)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Mar (Box 13, Folder 331-332)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Apr (Box 13, Folder 333-334)
        - Correspondence, 1891 May (Box 14, Folder 335-336)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Jun (Box 14, Folder 337-338)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Jul (Box 14, Folder 339)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Aug (Box 14, Folder 340-341)
        - Correspondence, 1891 Sep-Dec (Box 14, Folder 342)
        - Correspondence, 1892 Jan-Feb (Box 14, Folder 343)
        - Correspondence, 1892 Mar-Oct (Box 14, Folder 344)
        - Correspondence, 1893 May-Jul (Box 14, Folder 345)
        - Correspondence, 1893 Aug-Nov (Box 14, Folder 346)
        - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 14, Folder 347)
        - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 348)
        - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 14, Folder 349)
        - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 14, Folder 350)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Jan-Apr (Box 14, Folder 351)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Jun (Box 14, Folder 352)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Jul (Box 14, Folder 353)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Aug (Box 14, Folder 354)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Sep (Box 14, Folder 355)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Oct (Box 14, Folder 356)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Nov (Box 15, Folder 357)
        - Correspondence, 1898 Dec (Box 15, Folder 358)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Jan (Box 15, Folder 359)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Feb-Mar (Box 15, Folder 360)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Apr-May (Box 15, Folder 361)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Jun (Box 15, Folder 362)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Jul-Aug (Box 15, Folder 363)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Sep-Oct (Box 15, Folder 364)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Nov (Box 15, Folder 365)
        - Correspondence, 1899 Dec (Box 15, Folder 366)
        - Correspondence, 1900 Jan (Box 15, Folder 367)
        - Correspondence, 1900 Feb-Mar (Box 15, Folder 368)
        - Correspondence, 1900 Apr-May (Box 15, Folder 369)
        - Correspondence, 1900 Jun-Aug (Box 15, Folder 370)
        - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 371)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Jan (Box 15, Folder 372)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Feb (Box 15, Folder 373)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Mar-Apr (Box 15, Folder 374)
        - Correspondence, 1902 May-Aug (Box 15, Folder 375)
        - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 15, Folder 376)
        - Correspondence, 1904 Feb-Aug (Box 15, Folder 377)
        - Correspondence, 1904 Sep (Box 15, Folder 378)
        - Correspondence, 1905 Oct 19 (Box 15, Folder 379)
        - Correspondence, 1906 Mar-Apr (Box 15, Folder 380)
        - Correspondence, 1906 Jun (Box 15, Folder 381)
        - Correspondence, 1906 Jul (Box 16, Folder 382)
        - Correspondence, 1906 Aug (Box 16, Folder 383)
        - Correspondence, 1906 Sep-Oct (Box 16, Folder 384)
        - Correspondence, 1907 Jan-Apr (Box 16, Folder 385)
        - Correspondence, 1907 May-Jul (Box 16, Folder 386)
        - Correspondence, 1907 Aug (Box 16, Folder 387)
        - Correspondence, 1907 Sep (Box 16, Folder 388)
        - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 389)
        - Correspondence, 1910 Jul 29 (Box 16, Folder 390)
        - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 391)
        - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 392)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Jun (Box 16, Folder 393)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Jul (Box 16, Folder 394)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Aug (Box 16, Folder 395)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Sep (Box 16, Folder 396)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Apr-Jun (Box 16, Folder 397)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Jul (Box 16, Folder 398)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Aug (Box 16, Folder 399)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Sep-Dec (Box 16, Folder 400)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Jul (Box 16, Folder 401)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Aug (Box 16, Folder 402)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Sep-Nov (Box 16, Folder 403)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Dec (Box 16, Folder 404)
        - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 405)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Jul (Box 16, Folder 406)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Aug (Box 16, Folder 407-408)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Sep (Box 17, Folder 409)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Oct (Box 17, Folder 410)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Nov (Box 17, Folder 411)
        - Correspondence, 1918 Aug-Sep (Box 17, Folder 412)
        - Correspondence, 1918 Oct (Box 17, Folder 413)
        - Correspondence, 1918 Nov (Box 17, Folder 414)
        - Correspondence, 1918 Dec (Box 17, Folder 415)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Jan (Box 17, Folder 416)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Feb (Box 17, Folder 417)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Mar (Box 17, Folder 418)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Apr (Box 17, Folder 419-420)
        - Correspondence, 1919 May (Box 17, Folder 421)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Jun-Jul (Box 17, Folder 422)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Aug-Sep (Box 17, Folder 423)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Nov-Dec (Box 17, Folder 424)
        - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 425)
        - Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 426)
      - Southrn, Frank
        - Correspondence, 1886-89 (Box 17, Folder 427)
        - Correspondence, 1890-1916 (Box 18, Folder 428)
        - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 429)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Jan-Sep (Box 18, Folder 430)
        - Correspondence, 1919 Oct-Nov (Box 18, Folder 431)
        - Correspondence, 1920-24 (Box 18, Folder 432)
        - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 433)
        - Correspondence, 1926-27 (Box 18, Folder 434)
      - Henri, Linda Craige
        - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 18, Folder 435)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Jan (Box 18, Folder 436)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Feb (Box 18, Folder 437-438)
        - Correspondence, 1902 Mar (Box 18, Folder 439-440)
        - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 18, Folder 441)
        - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 442)
      - Henri, Marjorie Organ
        - Correspondence, 1914-20 (Box 18, Folder 443)
      - Organ, Violet
        - Correspondence, 1923, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 444)
      - Others
        - Julia Gatewood, 1882 May 28 (Box 18, Folder 445)
        - Robert Gatewood, 1928 Aug 12 (Box 18, Folder 446)
      - Unidentified recipients
        See: Box 10, folders 265-268
    - Southrn, Frank
      See also: Correspondence with Robert Henri, boxes 17-18, folders 427-434
      - Lee, Theresa Gatewood and Richard H.
        - Correspondence, 1888-92 (Box 18, Folder 447)
        - Correspondence, 1896-1918 (Box 18, Folder 448)
    - Lee, Theresa Gatewood
      See also: Correspondence with Robert Henri, boxes 11-17, folders 283-426, and correspondence with Frank Southrn, box 18, folders 447-448
      - [A. Traber Gatewood?], 1909 Jul 23 (Box 18, Folder 449)
      - Debbie [Gatewood?], 1904-06 (Box 18, Folder 450)
      - John Robert [Gatewood?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 451)
      - Julia Ann Gatewood, 1903-04, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 452)
      - Julia Gatewood (niece), 1882 Apr 14 (Box 18, Folder 453)
      - Marjorie Henri, 1914-20, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 454)
      - Richard H. Lee, 1882, 1892 (Box 18, Folder 455)
      - Invitation, [1878] (Box 18, Folder 456)
    - Henri, Marjorie Organ
      See also: Correspondence with Robert Henri, box 18, folder 443, Correspondence with Theresa Gatewood Lee, box 18, folder 454
      - Violet Organ, 1926, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 457)
      - Violet and Mrs. Organ (Box 19, Folder 458)
      - Unidentified, 1927, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 459)
    - Others
      - Linda Craige Henri and Mr. and Mrs. T. Huston Craige, 1898-1900 (Box 19, Folder 460)
      - Dr. E. Stanley Perkins to Mr. Richard H. Lee, 1899 Nov 1 (Box 19, Folder 461)
      - Copies of Lee (Cozad)-Gatewood correspondence relating to property (Box 19, Folder 462)
      - Early [Cozad?] to [Henry Cozad], 1870 Sep 20 (Box 19, Folder 463)
  - OTHER CORRESPONDENCE
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified writer and recipient (Box 19, Folder 464)
      - Letter in unidentified hand, with note, "copy of that I gave Mr. -- Editor of Register, 1889 Oct 19 (Box 19, Folder 465)
      - Empty envelopes, 1889-1902 (Box 19, Folder 466)
- Writings, 1857-1929; Series II; 1.9; (5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series II, Writings, is organized into two subseries: Writings by Robert Henri and Writings by Others. The subseries are arranged by format.
  - WRITINGS BY ROBERT HENRI
    - Journals
      - Looseleaf journal entries, 1885 Feb 24-Mar 2 (Box 20, Folder 467)
      - "Journal of Art" one page, 1886 Sep 28-Oct 4 (Box 20, Folder 468)
        Accompanied by bottom half of printed list of medical books
      - Journal, 1890 Oct-Nov (Box 20, Folder 469)
      - Journal with accounts at back, and nine pages of sketches in pen and ink and in pencil, 1890-91 (Box 20, Folder 470)
        Entries from Dec 15 1890 to Jan 16 1891, Aug 1-12 1891
      - Looseleaf journal entries, 1894-95 (Box 20, Folder 471)
        Entries from Apr 4 1894 to Apr 28 1894; Nov 15-16, 1894; Mar 7-8, 1895
      - Looseleaf journal entries in shorthand, 1928-29 (Box 20, Folder 472)
        Entries from Oct 21-29 1928, Dec 20 1928 to Jan 14 1929, and entry for May 3 1929
      - Journal in shorthand, 1929 Jan-Feb (Box 20, Folder 473)
      - Notes on a visit to London (Box 20, Folder 474)
    - Art Spirit
      - Holograph and typescript writings, gathered for inclusion in Art Spirit, 1906-23, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 475-483)
      - Typescript, corrected in Henri's hand (Box 20, Folder 484-486)
      - Typescript, corrected in Henri's hand (Box 21, Folder 487-494)